http://www.boneham.co.uk/privacy-policy

This website uses cookies to enhance your experience.
I agree
More information
Privacy Policy1. Introduction and purposeBoneham and Turner Ltd is registered in England and Wales, No. 00151276. Boneham and Turner Ltd manufactures and supplies precision engineered products and associated services to predominately business-to-business customers.Boneham and Turner Ltd is committed to protecting the privacy and security of its customer’s personal data by complying with all data protection laws applicable to the United Kingdom.The purpose of this privacy policy is to clearly clarify the information the company collects, how it is used, shared and managed. This notice also informs our valued customers on how to manage marketing preferences, the data we hold and confirms your rights as a customer of Boneham and Turner Ltd.The Data Controller responsible for the privacy of your data is Boneham and Turner Ltd.2. Why we collect personal dataBoneham & Turner Ltd is required to hold, maintain and use certain information about individuals and organisations. The company does this in order to process and manage order fulfilment, contractual obligations and customer expectation.Any personal information collected relates only to the individuals role as an employee or agent of the customer business.This information can include customers, suppliers, business contacts, employees and other people the organisation has a relationship with or may need to contact in order to conduct normal business operations.3. The legal bases we work toThe EU General Data Protection Regulation “GDPR” (Regulation EU 2016/679), sets out in law a number of different reasons why a company may collect and process your personal data. In order for Boneham and Turner Ltd to fulfil contractual obligations and a competitive customer experience, the company may use the following lawful basis for processing personal information:Contractual Obligations: In most circumstances we require your personal data to comply with contractual obligations. For example, a contractual order can only be fulfilled by collecting your delivery address to deliver your purchase. These details will be passed onto our contracted courier to deliver the parcel.Legitimate Interest: We require your data to pursue our legitimate business interests in a way which might reasonably be expected to run our business, whilst not impacting your interests, freedoms and fundamental rights. For example, we may use your order history to send potential offers or new product information. Use sales history to identify trends to raise inventory levels and production runs to keep up with demands. We may use your address details to send an up-to-date catalogue.Consent: Boneham and Turner offer the ability to opt-in to news about the company. We don’t currently use direct marketing and do not rely on consent as a legal basis.4. When we collect data about youBoneham and Turner Ltd has collected and holds your data because one of the following interactions has taken place (using your employing business or personally):When you have become a customer of Boneham and Turner Ltd. Completing an order over the phone, email, fax or website.When you requested a quotation from Boneham and Turner Ltd by phone, email, fax or our website.When a request has been made for a catalogue, product information or personal representation.When you have visited us at a tradeshow and requested information on our products and services.When you have completed forms or surveys issued by us via email, website or mail.5. The type of information we collect about youBoneham and Turner Ltd manufactures and supplied products predominantly on a business-to-business contractual basis. Personal data collected by the company in a business to business transaction, relates only to an individual’s role as an agent for their employer or business in fulfilling the business-to-business contract. Boneham and Turner endeavours not to collect any personal data other than that which is required to complete that contract.Data collected from non-business-to-business transactions is not used for any other purpose but fulfil the contractual obligations of that order.Identity Data (used to identify you): Title, name, last name. If a transaction is collected, we may have images recorded on CCTV.Contract Data (used to contact you): Billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.Financial Data: Boneham and Turner does not store payment card detailsTransactional Data (previous transactions): orders, receipts, credits, refunds and products purchasedBoneham and Turner also store details of the businesses or employing company’s interaction with us through online forms, email correspondence and details of visits and exhibition visits.Details of visits to our websites and the referral siteInformation gathered by the use of cookies (please see our cookies policy)6. Why and how we use your personal dataBoneham and Turner endeavour to give the best possible customer experience and service. One way in which we achieve this goal is to understand you as a customer. We do this by combining the data we have and using it improve our service to you. Data privacy laws allow us to do this as part of our legitimate interest in understanding our customers and fulfilling our contractual and record keeping obligations.Below is a data map of how we use your data, the type of data we capture for that process and the legal bases that allows us to use your data and control that use.Business ProcessType of Personal DataLawful basis for processing personal dataNew customer registrationIdentityContractual obligationContactOnline account purchaseIdentityContractual obligationLegitimate interestsContactFinancialTransactionalMarketing and CommunicationsOnline guest purchaseIdentityContractual obligationLegitimate interestsContactFinancialTransactionalAccount purchase by phone or emailIdentityContractual obligationLegitimate interestsContactFinancialTransactionalMarketing and CommunicationsCustomer correspondence (Feedback, complaint, returns etc.)IdentityContractual obligationLegitimate interestsContactMarketing and CommunicationsLiterature requestsIdentityContractual obligationContactOpt in to Email newsIdentityConsentContactMarketing and CommunicationsSocial media engagementIdentityContractual obligationContactTradeshow visitsIdentityConsentLegitimate interestsContactUsageMarketing and CommunicationsFeedback surveysIdentityLegitimate interestsContactUsageMarketing and CommunicationsOrganise a representative to visitIdentityContractual obligationLegitimate interestsContactUsageMarketing and CommunicationsConsented business referralsIdentityConsentLegitimate interestsContactUsageMarketing and CommunicationsOnsite visits and events CCTVIdentityLegal complianceLegitimate interestsData analytics during web browsingIdentityLegitimate interestsContactTechnicalUsageProfilePublically accessible data when consent is given to the source i.e. companies house or LinkedInIdentityContractual obligationLegitimate interestsContact7. How is your personal data sharedBoneham and Turner share your personal information only with those persons who need to handle it so to manufacture and supply the products ordered. We also may share it with companies within the Boneham Group who are part of the supply chain in delivering goods to you.We will also share data with suppliers who provide services to us which require access to your personal information only and with re-sellers, distributors and agents involved in delivering the services we provide where necessary for them to do so.Boneham and Turner use trusted third-party card payment gateways and do not store credit card details.Lastly, we may also provide your personal information to fraud prevention agencies. This is to protect the Boneham Group of companies and our customers, to keep our systems secure, or where it’s necessary to protect either yours or our best interests.Boneham and Turner do not share your data with third parties for their own business purposes.8. How we protect your personal dataBoneham and Turner knows how much data security matters to all customers. Data is treated with the upmost care. Websites are secured using ‘https’ technology with high level protection at server level. Our ‘Data Protection Policy’ and ‘Information Security Policy’s’ strictly govern the way we handle, process and store data, in both physical and digital form.We continually look for new methods of cyber protection and resilience programmes to ensure data safety and business continuity.9. Where your personal data may be processedBoneham and Turner Ltd stores data on secure servers in the UK. Sometimes we will need to share your data with third parties. For example couriers or software providers. Sometimes these may fall outside of the European Economic Area (EEA). Any transfer of your personal data will follow applicable laws and we will treat the information under the guiding principles of this Privacy Policy.International customersBy using our services or providing your personal data to us, you expressly consent to the processing of your personal data by us or on our behalf within the UK. You have the right to ask us not to process your data in certain ways, and if you do so, we will respect your wishes.10. Your rights over your personal dataYou have the right to request:Information about the collection and use of your personal data (as outlined in this Privacy Policy or by contacting us).Access to the personal data we hold about youThe correction of inaccurate, out of date or incomplete personal dataYour personal information to be erased, not processed or collected where there is no good reason for us to continue processing it. Otherwise known as `the right to be forgotten`.We stop using your personal data for marketing purposesComplain to the data protection regulator (see contacting the regulator).To protect confidentiality of your information, we will ask you to verify your identity. Requests may take up to one month to process11. Retention of InformationWhen we collect or process your personal information we will only keep it for as long as it is necessary to provide our services to you and to comply with our legal and contractual obligations.At the end of that retention period, your data will be either deleted or anonymised. In the latter scenario the data will be used in a non-identifiable way for statistical and business planning purposes.12. Contact usIf you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:Email: info@boneham.co.ukPost:  Boneham and Turner Ltd, Oddicroft Lane, Sutton in Ashfield, Nottinghamshire, NG17 5FBCookie PolicyWhat are Cookies? A cookie is a text file comprising of information that can be stored by a web browser between internet pages. When someone uses a web browser to access the internet their browser can create cookies which are stored on the user’s computer. Cookies are not programs and as such, cannot contain viruses or other malicious software. They are purely a string of text and numbers.Two main types of cookies exist, these are session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies have a lifetime span of a single browsing session. When a user closes their web browser the session cookie information is automatically removed from their computer.Persistent cookies are stored by the user's web browser even when the web browser has been closed down. Why does it do this? So that the next time a user returns to the website that initially established the cookie, the web site can read information back from that cookie and enhance the user experience.How does Boneham.co.uk use Cookies?1. Boneham and Turner Ltd uses Google Analytics to record information about how and who is visiting the website. Google sets five different cookies. The use of these cookies is to analyse whether users visit for the first time, or are returning. Cookies used by Google Analytics do not contain any personal information, with no personal identifiers present.More information on how Google uses cookies and Googles privacy information can be found here https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/60042452. The Boneham and Turner website uses a persistent Cookie to remember user’s login credentials when selected by the user using the provided tick box.3. Boneham and Turner does not store credit card details.How to Delete, Control and Remove CookiesPlease be aware, by deleting or restricting the use of cookies on the Boneham website, users will be unable to experience the full benefit of the planned customer experience throughout the site.The following browsers provide details on managing cookies within their browsing software.How to manage cookies in Firefox*How to manage cookies in Chrome*How to manage cookies in Safari*How to manage cookies in Microsoft Edge*You can find instructions on how to control the use of cookies, or delete cookies from your computer at http://www.aboutcookies.org (English only)
Loading
